NO BOY NO CRY ore zenshin GO
no boy, no cry, I advance go!
shounen yo kiite kure
hey boys, listen up
ningen nante taishita mon ja nai sa
humans aren't such a big deal
ashita nante moui ranai kara
who needs tomorrow anyway
nigitta kobushi wo kakusu na yo
so don't hide your fists
fuan ni yume wo
you're not old enough
uri tobasu hodo mada oiborechainai daro
to sell your dreams away to uncertainty
shounen yo kokoro no jyuu no
hey boys, you're the only ones
hikigane wo hikeru no wa kimi dake sa
who can pull the trigger in your heart
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
doushi yo mo naku kudaranai
we're living in this senseless, ridiculous,
kono subarashii sekai ni tattaima ikiteiru kara
awesome world right at this moment,
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
subete no hontou to uso wo
don't forget every truth or lie
kesshite wasurete shima wa nai you ni
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
shinu ni wa mosugiru darou
we're way too young to die
shiraketa tsura ga naranderu karappo no kono machi de
in this empty town lined with empty faces
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids took off
kaze no nai kono yoru ni
into this windless night
nanika wo kaeyou to shiteru kara
because they want to change something
Sasuke!
You punk!
What's with... this guy?
Why...?
Damn it...
Is this the best you've got...?
If this is all you've got,
I still don't need to use that...
What?
You haven't realized it?
I... haven't used my Sharingan.
Don't mock me!
You don't have enough strength
or desire...
You are weak.
Why you are weak?
Because you don't have enough... hatred.
If I kept playing comrade with you guys...
I wouldn't have... been able to get...
...this much power!
That's right... I need...
Both power... and hatred...
in order to catch up with him.
{Itachi and Sasuke
{An Existence
{Too Far Apart
Nii-san... I'll get off.
Don't push it...
Okay...
Oh...
What's up?
This is the place...
where Father works, right?
Yeah... The headquarters
of the Leaf Police Force.
I was curious about it from before,
but why's the Uchiha Clan crest
on the Police Force mark?
Oh... so you noticed, huh?
Of course...
Yeah... Let me see...
To put it simply...
it seems the previous generations
of the Uchiha Clan
set up and established the Police Force.
So they used their own crest for
the symbol mark of this organization.
From olden times,
the Uchiha Clan has always been
in charge of protecting
the public and the peace of this village.
The Uchiha crest is
a testament to the proud clan.
The Uchiha Clan has gotten small now.
But even now, nearly all members
belong to this first force here.
and contribute to maintaining
peace in the village.
Only even more exceptional Shinobi
can crack down on the crimes
committed by Shinobi, so...
Sure enough, father's awesome!
Leaf Police Force
Are you going to enter the Police Force, too?
Well... I'm not sure...
Why not?!
When I grow up, I'm also going
to enter the Police Force, so!
Father's also coming to
tomorrow's entrance ceremony.
It's the first step to my dream.
That's right.
You're late... What were you doing?
Father...
I have something to talk to you about.
Come quickly.
That's my boy.
You've come this far just half a year
after being promoted to Chunin.
About tomorrow's special mission...
I've decided to go with you, too.
Tomorrow?
If you complete this mission, Itachi...
your entrance into
the ANBU Black Ops is almost assured!
You understand, right?
You don't have to be so worried.
More importantly...
Umm... Father...
Tomorrow's my...
Tomorrow's mission will be
a very important mission not just for you,
but for the Uchiha Clan!
I'm quitting tomorrow's mission, after all.
What're you doing talking insanity?!
You should know how important
a day tomorrow is!
I'm going to Sasuke's Academy
entrance ceremony tomorrow...
The general rule is for relatives
to attend the Academy entrance ceremony.
There was the notice, right... Father?
I get it already.
I'll go to the Academy...
Your left leg...
Be sure to ice it.
Right...
Nii-san... He's so distant...
Entrance Ceremony
Everyone! Congratulations
on your entrance!
From here on, please work very hard
towards striving for the Shinobi path.
And I'd like you to bring further prosperity
to the Hidden Village in the Leaf.
Gee... I remember
the time when Itachi-kun entered.
Just what I'd expect from his brother.
Thank you for your help with both boys.
Oh, it's nothing like that.
The first prodigy since the beginning
of the Academy...
There were no students
as exceptional as that boy.
That's a bit too much praise.
Not at all...
I'm hopeful for you, too.
Become a fine Shinobi
like your big brother.
Yes.
Hey... That's Uchiha, right?
Yeah.
I wonder... if he's awesome, too.
Hmm... Must be.
Recess at last! What a drag.
I'm still not used to this place...
You want some too, Shikamaru?
I mean, all of your recesses
have become meal times.
That's my boy...
I've great confidence
you'll make it great in ANBU.
This won't do!
Won't do!
I've got a long way... to go...
Really...
You should rest your body
on your days off at least.
You don't have to push it.
I heard... that nii-san graduated
from the Academy in just one year.
The times are different, then and now.
Besides, that kid is a bit special, so...
That's my boy...
Now, I'm going to hand out
the report cards for the first half.
"Taijutsu: 1st in class and academy"
"Ninjutsu: 1st in class and academy"
Do a fine job in this vein like
your big brother.
Father... I wanted you to say,
"That's my boy," to me...
What did you say?
What do you mean you can't participate
in the assembly tomorrow?!
You don't understand your own position!
I'm setting out on a mission tomorrow.
What're they doing this late
at night with the lights off?
What mission?!
I can't say...
It's a top secret mission.
Itachi... You also have the role
of the pipe which connects the clan
with the keystone of the village.
You know that, don't you?
Yeah...
Keep that well in mind!
And come to tomorrow's assembly!
Sasuke...
Get to bed after
you've gone to the bathroom.
Right...
What're you doing hanging around
this late at night?
Get to bed!
Okay.
"Report Card"
Father only thinks about you, nii-san...
Am I loathsome to you?
It's okay.
It's logical for Shinobi to be
ill-thought of by people, so...
That's not how I feel...
Nii-san's right.
I really do... think ill of him...
Excellence is not easy at all.
If you have power,
you become alienated and also arrogant.
Even if you're coveted
and sought after at first.
But, we only have each other
for siblings.
I will continue to exist with you
as a wall you must get over...
Even if I'm ill-thought of...
That's what a big brother is.
Is Itachi home?!
I have something to
talk to you about. Come out!
Why's everyone gathered here?
There are two people who didn't come
to yesterday's assembly.
Why didn't you come?!
He didn't go to the assembly Father
was talking about last night, after all.
I understand that when you enter ANBU,
you get roped into various
troublesome things.
Your father also said something
like that in your defense.
But for us, we don't intend
to treat you special.
Understood. I shall be careful next time.
Now I'm going to have
to ask you to leave.
Right... But before that,
there's a little more I want to ask you...
It's about Uchiha Shisui who threw himself
into the Nakano River to kill himself.
Threw himself?!
The other person who didn't come
to the assembly is that Shisui.
As I recall, you adored him
like a real older brother.
I see... I hadn't seen him at all recently.
That's too bad.
And we the Police Force have decided
to launch an all-out investigation.
Investigation?!
This is the will Shisui wrote.
The analysis of the handwriting
has been completed.
No mistake, he did indeed write it.
If there are no murder leads,
then what's the investigation?
It'd be easy for a person who can use
Sharingan to copy handwriting, you see...
The most adept Uchiha.
The man feared as Shisui,
"the Instantaneous Man."
He was a man who would take
the lead no matter what the mission
if it was for the sake of the clan.
It's tough to think that
such a man would leave something
like this and kill himself.
You shouldn't judge people...
only on looks and speculation.
For the time being,
I leave the will with you.
Take that and you request cooperation
in the investigation from ANBU Black Ops.
Understood...
I hope we get a lead.
Also, we have a different route
to ANBU Black Ops.
We'll know right away if you do something
like crushing the investigation request.
Why don't you just come right out
and say it?
You suspect me, right?
Yeah. That's right, you little punk...
Listen up, Itachi.
Just try doing something
like betraying the clan and...
it'll cost you!
I told you before.
You shouldn't judge people...
only on looks and speculation.
It's because you take the liberty to
judge me as patient and take me lightly.
Clan... Clan...
You measure incorrectly
the size of your own vessels
and don't know the depth of mine,
so you grovel there...
I've never seen him like this...
Shisui... was monitoring you recently...
Half a year after entering ANBU...
the strangeness of your behavior
couldn't be overlooked.
What the hell are you thinking?
Fixated on the organization,
fixated on the clan,
fixated on the name.
It's a dreadful thing that constrains
oneself and labels one's own vessel.
And it's a foolish thing...
that fear and hate...
what one has never seen or known...
Stop, Itachi!
What the hell's the matter
with you?!
Itachi...
You've been a little strange lately.
I'm not strange at all.
I'm carrying out my own role...
That's it.
Then why didn't you come last night?
In order to elevate myself higher...
What're you talking about...?
My vessel is dismayed
at this foolish clan!
From olden times,
the Uchiha Clan has all along
been in charge protecting
the peace of this village.
The Uchiha crest is a testament
to the proud clan.
That's my boy...
I've great confidence
you'll do great in ANBU Black Ops.
Because you're fixated
on insignificant things like clans...
you lose sight of what's truly important.
True change cannot be made if stuck
within the restrictions of regulations,
and constrained predictions
and imagination...
Saying such arrogant things!
Enough! You'll be imprisoned
if you say any more foolish nonsense.
Excellence is not easy at all.
If you have power,
you become alienated and also arrogant...
even if you're coveted
and sought after at first...
Why... Nii-san...?
What do you say?!
I can't tolerate it anymore...
Captain, order imprisonment!
Nii-san! Stop it already!
I'm not the one who killed Shisui.
But I apologize for
my numerous slips of the tongue.
I'm very sorry...
Recently, it seems he's been up
to his ears in ANBU Black Ops missions
and was a little tired...
Captain!
The ANBU Black Ops is a force
under the direct control of Hokage-sama...
Even we the Police Force can't arrest him,
if we don't have an arrest warrant.
And as for Itachi...
I will take the responsibility
and monitor him.
Please...
Understood...
With this, you've woken up, right?
We had a hindrance back at that time...
But it won't be like that this time.
I'll show you...
the true power of Sharingan.
hitotsu hitotsu omoidaseba
when I recalled the parts one by one,
subete wakatteita kigashite ita no ni
I felt as though I had understood everything
iroaseta kotoba wa
faded words
boku no sugu soba ni oite atta
which I kept so close to me
kotae no denai yoru to
speechless nights,
a hint of warmth,
hitokira no nukumori to
and this distant yearning for you
haruka kanata no akogare to
I live,
tada sore dake wo
simply repeating this cycle
kurikaeshi boku wa ikite iru
held in my two hands
kono ryoute ni kakaete iru mono
a droplet of time
toki no shizuku
softly clutching forgotten memories
sotto nigirishimete wasureta kioku
lost words
nakushita kotoba
I'll keep these thoughts...
kono omoi wa
Give me all you've got, Naruto.
Or is this all you've got?
You were talking impudently
about your Ninja Way
and this is all you've got?
You've gotta be kidding! Right now,
you're not even worth beating!
Next time:
"Father and Son. The Cracked Family Crest."